<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homes on R-Ladies Philly</title>
    <link>/home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homes on R-Ladies Philly</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 R-Ladies Philly</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/about/</guid>
      <description>About Us We are the Philadelphia chapter of R-Ladies Global, a world-wide organization that promotes gender diversity in the R community and in data science more broadly. While our group name does have ‘R’ and ‘Ladies’ in the title, we welcome all individuals who share our values and follow our code of conduct and who have an interest in data science, regardless of proficiency with R.
Since our first meetup in January 2018, R-Ladies Philly has grown to a highly active, diverse and community-driven group, with:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent Posts</title>
      <link>/home/posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/posts/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Board</title>
      <link>/home/board/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/board/</guid>
      <description>Meet our board members Darina Chudnovskaya, MSc Darina is a data analyst at a hospital in the Philadelphia area. She uses R to run statistical tests and build models for epidemiological studies with the goal of developing patient interventions for disease prevention. She grew up in Philadelphia. Darina joined R Ladies Philly to meet other R enthusiasts.
Karla Fettich, PhD Karla works as Head of Algorithm Development at Orchestrall, where she leads behavioral data analytics efforts and predictive model development for healthcare IT innovation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News</title>
      <link>/home/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/news/</guid>
      <description> R-Ladies Philly has been featured in news and other media:
6/1/2018 - Podcast with The Data Lab 4/10/2018 - Interview with Wharton Customer Analytics Initiative 1/3/2018 - Article by technical.ly Philly </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sponsors</title>
      <link>/home/support/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/support/</guid>
      <description> R-Ladies Philly is fortunate to receive support from several amazing organizations. Contact us to learn more about becoming a sponsor.
RStudio R consortium WeWork Penn Dental Temple University Center City Drexel LeBow College of Business Penn Institute for Urban Research Orchestrall </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/home/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/contact/</guid>
      <description>Reach out by email if would like to help plan, sponsor, or host an event. We welcome volunteers!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tags</title>
      <link>/home/tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/tags/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>